我们，是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文！
and Steven!
二号
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
草
校对
Husky
特效
presisco
压制
时间轴 依依/presisco
你刚刚看到了吗?
Did you see that?
咣当!嘭的一下!
Wapoosh!Just wapoosh!
很棒啊,紫晶
That's great, Amethyst.
你进步的真快
You're getting so fast.
不!刚才那下糟透了!
No! This is worse!
今天早上的时候它还发出嗖的声音!
This morning,it was like wsshh!
嗖的一下!快极了,嗖,嗖嗖!
Just wsshh! Superfast,like wsshh, wsshh!
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我想你今天
I think this is why
休息一下会比较好
a day off would be good for you.
你不能总是想着
You should take a break
怎么做掉铁石英
from obsessing over Jasper.
呃,你确定我们必须今天去那里?
Ugh, are you sure we have to do this now?
当然!
Yes!
拜访一下橄榄石和青金石会很有趣的!
Visiting Peridot and Lapis will be so much fun!
是啊,一说到"有趣",我马上能联想到青金石
Yeah, 'cause when I think "fun," I think Lapis.
不知道她们最近在做什么
I wonderwhat they're up to.
可能已经把对方都逼疯了吧
Maybe they drove each other crazy
然后一把火把谷仓烧了
and burnt the barn down.
喔啊
Whoa.
她们的确对谷仓做了不少改动
They sure did something to the barn.
但是,波莱特,我需要你.
But, Paulette, I need you.
哦,快放手吧,佩西
Oh, get over it,Percy.
换个人做友谊手环吧
Go make another friendship bracelet.
可不是嘛
Seriously.
橄榄石与青金石的这种组合在舍友情景剧中非常常见
青金石,橄榄石,嗨!
Lapis, Peridot, hi!
史蒂文!
Steven!
又见面真是太好了!
It's so good to see you again!
我也是,青金石
You, too, Lapis.
紫晶!
Amethyst!
你今天看上去有所不同啊
Something looks different about you.
怎么不同?
Like what?
和上次见面时比
Have you grown taller
你好像长高了?
since the last timeI saw you?
没,还很矮
Nope, still short.
不用谢
You're welcome.
开玩笑啦
For the joke.
哇哦,你们看上去真不错
Wow. You guysare looking good.
我超喜欢你们对谷仓的改动
And I love what you did to the barn.
嗷,我知道它很棒
Aw, I know.
但等等,等等!
But wait, wait!
你们一定要看看谷仓的内部!
You guys have to see the inside!
青金石,带我们飞进去!
Lapis, fly us in!
不
No.
欢迎来的我们母星外的家
Welcome to our home away from Homeworld.
喔啊!
Whoa!
你们把墙壁做成了水族箱!
You made the wallan aquarium!
呃呃呃!
Eww!
你们刻意做的这些装修?
You did all this stuff on purpose?
我是说,简直像你们把东西随便扔一堆
Like, you didn't just knock over a bunch
然后说"呃,以后再收拾"
of paint cans and go,"Enh, just leave it"?
哦不,整个谷仓的装修都是非常有意义的
Oh, no. This was all very intentional.
是这样的,当时我有个主意:既然我们可以用声音创作音乐
You see, I had this idea:"What if we made music,
那为什么不可以用物体创作呢?
but, instead of sounds,we used things?"
真是蠢透了
That's dumb.
伙计们,这是艺术!
Guys, that's art!
艺术?
Art?
听上去好蠢!
That sounds ridiculous!
我们一直都管这些东西叫"咪嗼"
I've been calling it meep morp.
给你看看我们的嗼嗼
Let us show youour morps.
这个作品叫"哇,谢谢"
This piece is called Wow, Thanks.
它表达了人们因为沟通的隔阂而挣扎
It represents the struggles of intercommunication.
录音带是将我们两人的经历
The tape is the ribbon that binds
连结在一起的桥梁
our experienceon Earth together.
它没什么实用意义
It has no functional purpose.
只是能让我心里难受而已
It just makes me feel bad.
这是我的咪嗼
Here's my meep morp.
它是个球棒
This is a baseball bat.
它让我想起了玩棒球的时光
It reminds me of when I played baseball.
这是史蒂文给我的树叶
This is the leaf Steven gave me.
它让我想起...史蒂文给了我一片树叶
It reminds me of the time Steven...gave me a leaf.
嘿,对啊,我也记得!
Hey, yeah, it reminds me of that, too!
我感觉被囚禁了
I just feel trapped.
这是表达那几千年
Is this one about the thousands of years
你被困在镜子中的事吗?
you spent trapped in a mirror?
不
No.
我只是很喜欢那个电视剧
I just really like that show.
哦,紫晶,你会爱死这个的.
Oh, Amethyst,you'll love this one.
瞧瞧
Check it out.
这是一堆马桶?
They're toilets?
没错!
Right!
真不敢想我还能有什么好点子
What will I think of next?!
这代表了我被关在
This represents the time I spent imprisoned
你卫生间里的那段时光,史蒂文
in your bathroom, Steven.
我管它叫"有人使用"
I call it Occupied.
这是一部合作品
It's a collaborative piece.
真是太精彩了
It's amazing.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你不需要明白啊
What's there to get?
是水!
It's water!
从马桶里喷出来的水!
Shooting out of toilets!
我在家里也能看到啊
I can see that at home.
好吧,我知道你觉得这挺没意思的
All right. I see you're not impressed.
但这个--别激动
But this -- hold on.
它--这就是我们一直在等的压轴戏
This -- this is what we've all been waiting for.
加上我控制金属的能力
With the power of my metal abilities,
它会让你们惊得裙子都飞走的!
I will impress the shirts right off of you!
嗒哒!
Ta-da!
这是个单石乐队!
It's a one-Gem metal band.
一呀,二呀,三呀,开始...
One, a-two, a-three, and...
嘛,我就练习了这么多
Welp, that's as far as I've practiced that.
你为什么不试试一次只用一个乐器呢?
Why don't you try one thing at a time?
因为我们有客人啊,青金石
Because we have guests, Lapis,
我们得让客人们高兴!
guests who must be impressed!
唔
Hmm.
我们可以一起表演
We can try it together.
对啊
Yeah.
这难道不是很棒吗?
Isn't this great?
不
No.
瞧瞧她们一直在做这么酷的东西
Look at all this cool stuff they're doing.
这些东西算什么!
This is all nothing!
她们一直都在谷仓里玩破烂
They've been out here playing with garbage.
但你不是很喜欢玩破烂吗?
But you love playing with garbage.
早就不玩了
Not anymore.
谁有时间浪费在这些破烂上?!铁石英还在外面游荡呢?!
Who has time for any that when Jasper is out there?!
啊,紫晶
Ah, Amethyst,
我,呃,尽量别在这里
I, uh, try not to use the J-word
随便说铁某的名字
so loosely around here.
我要去做点更有意义的事了
I'm gonna go dosomething useful.
哇哦,紫晶看上去完全无法理解嗼嗼!
Wow, Amethyst doesn't seem to understand morps at all!
不,她是因为其他原因不高兴的
No, it's something else:
紫晶发现
Amethyst found out
她本应该是铁石英那样高大的战士
she's supposed to be just like Jasper.
咩?
Meh?
前几天她被铁石英的打得惨败
Jasper took her down in a fight and, now,
这些天她一直想着怎样打回去
she's obsessed with getting a rematch,
来证明她足够好
to prove she's good enough.
唔
Hmm.
紫晶,小晶晶,紫老大
Amethyst,Ams, Big A.
你比铁石英强太多了
You are way better than Jasper.
什么?
What?
哦
Oh.
你都告诉她什么了?
What did you tell her?
我,呃...
I, uh...
你这是想啥呢,干嘛把自己跟铁石英比?
What are you even doing,comparing yourself to her?
哦紫晶,这太荒谬了
Oh, Amethyst,that's ridiculous.
我应该叫你荒谬晶
I should call you Ridiculousthyst.
哈!呀!
Hah! Yah!
我是认真的,紫晶和铁石英
I mean, seriously,Amethyst and Jasper
是两种完全不同的石英
are two completely different Quartzes.
当然,你们俩都来自地球
Sure, you're both from Earth,
但你们的出生地有天壤之别
but your Kindergartens are radically different.
啥?
What?
等—等等,什么?!
Hold --Hold on. What?!
我们都是在地球出生的?
We're both from Earth?
嘛,对呀
Well, sure.
紫晶,你来自主宝宝基地
Amethyst, you're from the Prime Kindergarten,
在第五区
in Facet 5.
而她来自副宝宝基地,在第九区
She's from the Beta Kindergarten, in Facet 9.
你们去过那个地方吗?
Have you seen that place?
没有!
No!
哦,好吧,你们应该去看看,这样你就能明白
Oh. Well, maybe you should,so you could see
其他的宝石是怎么做出来的的
how the other half was made.
粗制滥造!
Poorly!
不,认真的,咱们走吧
No, seriously.Let's go.
看完你就该释怀了吧
You'll get a kick out of this.
那是你的个人问题,波莱特
That's your problem,Paulette.
是你任由自己变成舠一族的
You let yourself become the kayak race.
太凄凉了
Cold.
呃,给我一秒钟
Um, just one second.
我想确认一下青金石一个人没问题
I want to check and make sure Lapis is okay.
嘿,青金石!你没问题吧??!
Hey, Lapis!Are you okay-y-y?!
没问题!
Yeah!
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
确定!
Yeah!
我要走了,但我很快就会回来!
I'm leavin',but I'll be back!
好!
Okay!
你需要什么东西吗?!
Do you need anything?!
不需要!
No!
你现在看的是第几季?!
What season is that?!
第三季!
3!
橄榄石,走吧
Peridot, let's go.
哦对,好
Okay, yeah.
工作时间
Business time.
你知道要把它放到哪里的!
You know what to do with this!
咱们到了,铁石英的出生地,副宝宝基地
Here we are, Jasper's origin:the Beta Kindergarten.
从地貌看副宝宝基地位于亚利桑那的羚羊峡谷
是我的问题吗?
Am I underwhelmed?
这里亮得刺眼
It's pretty bright out here.
全是红色的
It's red.
确实
No kidding.
红砂岩!哈!
Red sandstone! Ha!
这材料不能更差!
This is what I'm talking about.
这地方还没被炸烂也是很幸运
We're lucky this place hasn't blown away.
果然只能算"副",对不对?
Beta, am I right?
这是什么数学玩笑吗?
That's a math joke,right?
快来吧,这里还会更糟的
Come on.It get's worse.
我是说,这个地方成长环境还好
I mean, this place has got the right
我想也确实难得
growing conditions,in a pinch,
但它面积太小了!
I guess,but it's too small!
这里完全就是赶工做出来的
It was obviously a total rush job.
赶工?
A rush job?
内战进行到一半的时候
Halfway through the rebellion,
母星急于在地球上
Homeworld scrambled to generate
制造出更多的士兵
extra soldierson the ground.
瞧瞧这个:这些洞都没排成直线!
Look at this: the holes don't even line up!
就好像他们只是
It's like they just
随随便便找个地方打个孔
threw injectors down wherever.
哦,再看这个
Oh, and that one?
这个玛瑙是斜着出来的
This Carnelian came out sideways.
她只能斜着出来!
How could she not?
这些岩壁都是弯的!
The walls are curved!
简直可笑
What a joke.
惊了,难以置信
Man, I-I had no idea.
跟你讲,这真的会让感谢
I tell you, it really makes you appreciate
主宝宝基地的,紫晶
the Prime Kindergarten,Amethyst.
你的宝宝基地很有讲究的
Your Kindergartenwas so thought-through.
是,你可能的确在地下花的时间比较长
Sure, you might've spentextra time in the ground,
但除了这点你其他的先天条件都很优秀
but everything elseis stacked in your favor:
不错的地点,不错的出生洞穴
great location,great holes,
均匀的空间分配,连贯的洞穴尺寸
even spacing,consistent depth.
专业宝宝基地工程师才做得好
A real Kindergartener gets it right.
这个注射器发生了什么?
What happened to this injector?
理想情况下,洞穴该是垂直的
What you want to see is a vertical alignment;
出口应该呈现出清晰的轮廓,而不是斜角
no angle in the exit;a clean, strong silhouette.
这些洞穴里没有一个达成了指标!
None of these holes come close!
这个呢?
What about that one?
铁石英
Jasper.
这是铁石英的洞穴?
This is Jasper's hole?
它可真大!
It's huge!
哦,拜托
Oh, come on.
我们都知道她挺高的
We already know she's tall.
我们来近距离瞧一瞧它
Let's take a closer look.
一个宝宝基地工程师最明白--
A Kindergartener can tell a lot --
啊!怎样通过洞穴的出口观察--
Anh! -- about a Gem's makeup and --
呃!--宝石的构成和缺陷
Uh! -- flaws by their exit marks.
史蒂文
Steven.
哦
Oh.
啊!
Ah!
呜呼!
Oof!
谢了
Thanks.
啊!
Agh!
你瞧,问题在--
You see,the problem here --
等等. 哦,等下,呃
Wait.Oh, wait. Oh.
不,唔...
No, um...
这个地方--
Now this part --
唔
Hmm.
但是呢,如果你用脚步来测量
There's this thing where,if you count the steps
到底的距离,就能--
to the back, I can --
怎么了?
What is it?
她的洞里连摩擦融化石头的痕迹都有
She's even got frictional rock melt.
从洞口直到洞底都是玻璃的
It's glass all the way to the back.
事实上,我,呃...
Actually, I, uh...
从来没见过这么完美的洞穴
I've never seen an exit hole this perfect.
惹
Ugh.
所以她真的比我好
So it is true.
紫晶,这一点都不重要
Amethyst,that doesn't matter.
你是谁不取决于你来自哪里
Who you are isn't about where you came from;
取决于你想成为什么!
it's who you want to be!
取决于你努力的方向
It's what you've worked hard for.
取决于你所重视的事物. 这才是重要的
It's what you care about.That's what really matters.
对
Yeah.
你说的对!
Yeah, you're right!
-对!-没错!
-Yeah!-Yeah!
取决于我想要成为什么
It's about who I wanna be.
-没错!-没错!
-Yeah!-Yeah!
而我想成为那个宝石
And I wanna be the Gem
那个把铁石英打的满地找牙的宝石!
that beats Jasper into the dirt!
-没错!什么?!
-Yeah!-Huh?
等等,别!不要和她打!
Wait, no!Don't fight her!
你还不明白吗?
Are you not seeing this?
她是一个终极的石英战士
She's the ultimate Quartz!
我就要这么做,没错,不只是为了我自己
I'm doin' it, yeah,and not just for me,
为了所有其他在这里出生的家伙们
for all the weird holes out here,
比如这个伙计,还有这个小瘦子
like this guy,and skinny up there,
还有--还有这个乱七八糟的家伙!
and -- and --and this mess!
紫晶,这是--
Amethyst, that's --
对,哈!我打赌她肯定挺厉害的
Yeah, ha!I bet she was great.
不不不,等等
No.No, no, no, hold on.
有什么地方不对
Something's really wrong here.
这些痕迹是新的
These marks are new.
这个洞穴是最近才被挖开的
This hole's been dug out, recently.
会不会是土拨鼠干的?
Maybe it was a prairie dog?
超大的一只?
A...really big one?
唔
Hmm.
还有更多!
There's more!
喔啊
Whoa.
这些已经不是出口洞穴了
These aren't exit holes anymore.
那他们是用来干嘛的?
Then what are they?
啊!
Aah!
史蒂文!
Steven!
宝石怪物,被囚禁的?
Corrupted Gems,in cages?
为什么?!
Why?!
谁会想要这么做?!
Who would do this?!
就是她
That's who.
铁石英
Jasper.